Dorothy Wrinch Papers, 1901-1983 (bulk 1919-1975)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES VI. WRITINGS 1936-70
  - Research notes
    - Miscellaneous marked reprints by Wrinch and others (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
    - Marked reprintsundated (Box 19, Folder 11)
- SERIES VII. MODELS AND STRUCTURES, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS - Three-dimensional models]
  - Miscellaneous photographs and negatives (Box 20, Folder 1-5)
  - Diagrams of nets, cyclol, polyhedra, and patterns (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of twinned structures (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, possibly related to twinning theory (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Photographs and diagrams of twin crystals, leaves, twin models, misc. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Bohr's cyclol model, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS - Wooden Boxes for original models] (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Electron density maps (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Models of original cyclols (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Orders, receipts and descriptions (Box 20, Folder 13)
- SERIES VIII. SMITH COLLEGE MATERIAL
  - Proposed seminars, lectures, class descriptions, schedules, reading and class lists, notes 1940-42, 1953, 1956-57, 1970-71 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Seminar examinations 1942-61 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Smith student recommendations 1961-67 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Class and seminar lecture notes 1946-48, 1954-55, 1961, 1965, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous administration documentsundated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Symposium inspired by the life and works of D. Wrinch
    - Correspondence, program, quotes and speech 1976-77, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Senechal, Marjorie, ed. Structures of Matter and Patterns in Science: A Symposium inspired by the work and life of Dorothy Wrinch, 1894-1976. Schenkman Publishing Co., Cambridge MA 1980. (Box 22, Folder 2)
- SERIES IX. MISCELLANEOUS
  - Bibliographic references (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Lists of people (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Physical society 1937, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Memorials: Niels Bohr, Harry Sobotka 1963, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Kaempffert, Waldemar. "If science sat at the peace table," 1944 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Nicholson, J.W. "Oblate spheroidal harmonics and their applications," 1923 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Pearson, William B. Preprint of paper and draft of book Crystal Chemistry of Metals 1969 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Storycraft, Inc, "Prescription for living: report on cancer," 1954 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- SERIES X. PAMELA WRINCH 1927-1975, [see also SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE - Family - Pamela Wrinch]
  - Clippings, biographical information, government documents, and miscellaneous 1945, 1951-54, 1962-66 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - "What price ideological conformity? Soviet Science, A Symposium," reviewed by Pamela Wrinch. Problems of Communism, vol. 3, no. 2 1954. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "Public Policy, a yearbook of the Graduate School of Public Administration," Harvard University 1958. Contains "Sir Winston Churchill on the Military Requirements of Great Britain" by Pamela N. Wrinch (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "Research Note: Science and Politics: a commentary" by Kurt P. Tauber. Reprinted from World Politics vol. IV, no. 31952. (Box 25)
  - "Science and Politics in the USSR: The Genetics Debate" by Pamela N. Wrinch, reprinted from World Politics vol. III, no. 41951. (Box 25)
  - "The military strategy of Winston Churchill" by Pamela Wrinch, Department of Government, Boston University. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "On the quest for 'science' in international politics" by Pamela Wrinch, Some Problems in the study and teaching of international politics. Ed. Charles Ol Lerche Jr. and Burton M. Sapin. P. 68. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "Pamela's own book of pipe tunes and pipe games," undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Sir Winston Churchill on Britain's Role Towards Europe: Detachment and Combination. by Pamela Nicholson Wrinch, A dissertation to the Faculty of the Graduate School of Yale University in Candidacy for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy 1954 (Box 25)
- SERIES XI. NOTEBOOKS, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIAL - Data scrapbooks]
  - "Water," contains some diagrams 1950-51, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Diagrams and notesundated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, notes and diagrams, mostly on mineral structure 1938-1956, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Modelsundated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Clippings of pictures 1956-61, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Notes and pictures of modelsundated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Marked copy of "An organic chemical formulation of the amide and cyclol theories," undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Marked copy of "Structures for small peptides within the amide and cyclol systems" and clippingsundated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Lectures, diagrams, and class notesundated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reprints and diagrams 1939, 1952-53 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Notes, diagrams, and class materials 1951-56, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Notes, diagrams, and figure descriptionsundated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Model and diagram photographsundated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Notes, figures, and diagrams 1954, 1958, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Writings on vector functions, and reprints 1955, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Writings on hemoglobins 1948, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Writings on vector maps and diagramsundated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Writings on compounds, diagramsundated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Reprints by Wrinch and others, and notes 1939-47 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, reprints, and miscellaneous notes 1938-1947, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and correspondence 1930-1940 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Guest registry (Box 28)
  - Notes and reprints regarding vector maps 1946-55, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - On psychotherapy 1956, 1961-66 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Notes 1945 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Reprints 1948-53 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and reprints 1953-57, 1963-65 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - On proteinundated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, reprints, and notes - marked "utmost importance," 1945-53 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and reprints 1954-60 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, reprints, and correspondence 1950-53, 1959, 1962, 1967-68 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, reprints, and correspondence 1952-67 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and research grant proposals 1957-61 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Class and miscellaneous notes and diagrams 1956-57, 1965-67, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Notes and reprints 1963-67 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and notes on Woods Hole 1962-69 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Structures and vector mapsundated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Diagramsundated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Writing on mineralogy, symmetry, and twinning1965 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Woods Hole notes and clippings1966-68 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Notes1966-67 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Data scrapbooks (2)undated, [see also SERIES VII. MODELS AND STRUCTURES and SERIES XI. NOTEBOOKS] (Box 31-32)
  - Three-dimensional models (Box 33-35)
  - Master of Science and Doctor of Science diplomas, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS - Biographical information] (Map-case Flat file)
- BOOKS ON SHELF
  - Ayling, Jean (pseudonym). The Retreat from Parenthood. London: Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner and Co., Ltd.1930.
  - Stoops, R. Les Protéines: Rapports et Discussions. Brussels1953.